Dance Theater of Nepal collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 4: Moving images
  - Subseries B: Optical discs
    - Dance Theater of Nepal, 1996; 1998; 2003, AFC 2011/002: MV26; 1 videodisc (DVD): digital; 4 3/4 in.
      The recording contains three DTON performances. The first is a benefit concert held in 2003 at the 'Y' Theater. The second performance is the final production of Nepal '98 at Symphony Space, and the third, "Living Traditions" held in 1994 at a small venue called Cobies Place. Predominantly English.
    - Dance Theater of Nepal at Princeton University, November 18, 2000, AFC 2011/002: MV27; 1 videodisc (DVD): digital; 4 3/4 in.
      Video of DTON performance at Princeton on November 18, 2000.
    - DTON clips, undated, AFC 2011/002: MV28; 1 videodisc (DVD): digital; 4 3/4 in.
      Compilation of clips from MV26, including dances from the 'Y' Theater performance and Cobies Place. Predominantly English.
    - Raj Kapoor and musicians clips, undated, AFC 2011/002: MV29; 1 videodisc (DVD): digital; 4 3/4 in.
      Clips of Raj and others performing at Cobies Place for the "Living Traditions" Expo and Open Center in New York City for the Hamro Taal (Shared Journeys) Exhibit in 2006. In English and Nepali.
    - Pratt course: Drawing, Dancing, Culture with Professor Sherry Onna Handlin., AFC 2011/002: MV30; 1 videodisc (DVD): digital; 4 3/4 in.
      Video of Sherry’s Drawing, Dancing, Culture course she taught at Pratt Institute in New York. Raj is one of the guest speakers, who provided dance instruction and posed for a live sketch. In English.
    - Binita Poudyal and Friends present: Kathmandu Sanjh, a performance of Nepali Folk Music and Dance, AFC 2011/002: MV31; 1 videodisc (DVD): digital; 4 3/4 in.
      Binita Poudyal hosts a dance/dinner, at the Shangri-La restaurant in Queens, 2009, in celebration of receiving an award. Multiple dancers and musicians participate at the event. In English and Nepali.
    - Raj Kapoor and artists rehearsals, AFC 2011/002: MV32; 1 videodisc (DVD): digital; 4 3/4 in.
      Clips of Raj teaching students at different locations. Video by Sherry Onna Handlin. In English and Nepali.
    - Raj Kapoor and artists rehearsals, 1997-2000, Nepali (2/2), AFC 2011/002: MV33; 1 videodisc (DVD): digital; 4 3/4 in.
      Continuation of MV32.
    - Amber Gurung at Columbia University, 1998, AFC 2011/002: MV34; 1 videodisc (DVD): digital; 4 3/4 in.
      Musical performance at Columbia University in August, 1998. Introductions are in Nepali.
    - Dance Mandal presents, Charya Nritya: The Tantric Buddhist Dance of Nepal, 1995, AFC 2011/002: MV35; 1 videodisc (DVD): digital; 4 3/4 in.
      Educational video on tantric dances of Nepal, which includes the Manjushri dance. Begins with a brief history of Nepal and its religious traditions and stories. It also provides examples of different spiritual dances. In English.
    - Teej Festival 2003, 2005 Satya Narayan Temple Elmhurst, Queens New York, AFC 2011/002: MV36; 1 videodisc (DVD): digital; 4 3/4 in.
      Contains clips from the Teej Festival at the Satya Narayan Temple in Queens, New York, 2003 and 2005. At the festival women fast and feast to the god, Shiva. In Nepali.
    - Interview portraits with Nepalese performing artists, dancers and teachers, 2003; 2005, undated, AFC 2011/002: MV37; 1 videodisc (DVD): digital; 4 3/4 in.
      Video of interviews and performances of different artists. Highlighted interviewees include Charan Pradhan and Prajwal Vajracharya. The DVD also includes the entire footage from MV36, on the Teej Festival in Queens, New York. In English and Nepali.
- Oversize materials (Box 6)
  Includes original newspapers and posters.
  - Basanti D. Rai, 2010, Newspaper; Separated from Box 2 (Box-folder 6/46)
  - Originals, 1995-2010 (1/2), Newspaper; Separated from Box 2 (Box-folder 6/47)
  - Originals, 1995-2010 (1/2), Newspaper (Box-folder 6/48)
  - Oversized Posters (contains item numbers OS01-GR01 – OS01-GR10) (Box-folder 6/49)
  - First Time in America: Nepal Festival USA-2008, AFC 2011/002: OS01-GR01; 1 18 x 12 in. color poster.
  - Dance Theater of Nepal presents Seasons Nepali, AFC 2011/002: OS01-GR02; 1 17 x 10 3/4 in. color poster.
  - Basanti Rai proudly presents, The Live Concert, AFC 2011/002: OS01-GR03; 1 18 x 12 in. color poster.
  - The Himalayan Groups presents, Moon in the sky: Prem Raja Night with Nepali musical superstars, AFC 2011/002: OS01-GR04; 1 17 x 11 in. color poster.
  - Himalayan Music Groups presents, Aayo Nepali: Himalayan night, AFC 2011/002: OS01-GR05; 1 11 x 17 in. color poster.
  - Yam Baral, Nalina Chitrakar et. al performing at an event, AFC 2011/002: OS01-GR06; 1 11 x 17 in. color poster.
  - Moves imported from Nepal, AFC 2011/002: OS01-GR07
  - Subha Ratri, AFC 2011/002: OS01-GR08; 1 14 1/2 x 9 in. announcement of a benefit dinner hosted by the Dance Theater of Nepal.
  - Subha Ratri, AFC 2011/002: OS01-GR09; 1 18 x 12 in. announcement of a benefit dinner hosted by the Dance Theater of Nepal.
  - Ram Nagarlcoti, AFC 2011/002: OS01-GR10; 1 17 x 11 in. color photocopy of Ram Nagarlcoti, the leading artist, videographer, musician and dancer of Nepali performance art in America.